Contact

md.nazmulhudapiash@gmail.co

www.linkedin.com/in/kazi-nazmul-huda-41b1a5127 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Presentations Zoho

Languages

Finence

English (Full Professional)
Hindi (Professional Working)
German (Limited Working)

Kazi Nazmul Huda

Master's degree at Rhine-Waal University
Mönchengladbach, North Rhine-Westphalia, Germany

Summary

Hi, good to see you. Hope you can learn about my workability and qualifications within the next few minutes of your valuable time. Before you give an overview of my profile, I would like to represent a glance at myself.

A skilled, sharp, and dedicated web application developer with many years of personal involvement and 2 years of work experience. Keeps exploring different areas of information technology including data science. R, Jupiter Lab, or an application like QGIS are there on my taskbar while XAMPP or MariaDB always running on my OS. Highly interested to learn new technologies and tools for the analysis and implementation of web applications and Data manipulation-based platforms. Not a born star but steady and humble as I believe the ocean of knowledge just touches my feet.

Masters's student at Rhine-Waal University (Germany), studying information engineering in computer science. Through master's study, innovate and keep learning the power of data science and analysis. Technologies and research related to GIS technologies always interest me with high gravity. Highly interested in a job position that has the scope for learning and improving myself for the company. The capability of understanding new people, company cutler to self-improvement, following best practices, and working with anything exciting out of my comfort zone.

Experience

Incypro GmbH
PHP Developer
September 2022 - March 2023 (7 months)
Mallinckrodtstr. 4 D - 47877 Willich

Implement new features for an internal CRM software

* Developed software with Zend (Laminas) and Jquery interfaces

- * Learning procedure of Laminas Framework to understand the existing software structure for application development.
- * Maintenance and implementation of new module based on the requirement of the CRM users (Rodopi Personal GmbH)
- * Data analysis and query to find solutions for new features with MySql DML, DQL, and DDL
- * Jquery, Ajax, and javascript are used to enhance the user experience with the system.

P.I. Ocean Soft Tech

Junior Software Developer

October 2017 - April 2019 (1 year 7 months)

Level-4, 333, Old Elephant Road Dhaka . Bangladesh, 1205 Dhaka (Bangladesh)

Development of ERP software for maintaining Garments Production and Merchandising

- *UI Design and decision-making to achieve Business efficiency
- *Develop the application with PHP 5 framework Codeigniter. Web building blocks like CSS, bootstrap, and Ajax are used to implement the Frontend.
- *Database design and manipulation with Mysql following the instruction of the senior developer.
- *Find the complex solution based on the business model with the Export-Import regulation for multiple countries.
- *The agile model followed the tools like FileZilla and git.
- *Maintain the A2 hosting for the update and maintenance of projects.

SOFTANIS

Junior Web Developer January 2017 - May 2017 (5 months)

Dhaka, Bangladesh

- *Frontend development of websites with WordPress CMS
- *Website design with building blocks of the web, such as HTML, CSS, Bootstrap
- *Google Calendar API integration with ZOHO CRM

Education

Rhine-Waal University

Master's degree, Computer and Information Sciences, General · (2019 - 2021)

Daffodil International University computer science and engineering · (2014 - 2017)